Jim Taylor

+44 (0) 7851 781 469 | jim@jimtaylor.space | Southfields, London

Summary

Full stack Laravel/JS developer with experience in DevOps/Cloud. Oxford grad and former entrepreneur.



Skills

Certifications: AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate (Sep 2019). Laravel certification (Jan 2020). Recent work with: Laravel 6 and 7, PHP 7+, Laravel vapor, Vue.js,, MySql, Ubuntu, AWS (S3, TSQS, SNS, Textract, Rekognition, RDS etc.), Docker and Docker swarm, Gitlab, Vuetify, Bootstrap 4, Tailwind CSS, Tabula, Tesseract, Autho. Playing with: Figma, Adonis.js, Mongo, GCP, Ionic, Redis, Terraform, DynamoDB, GraphQL, Elasticsearch. Business skills: Sales (B2B and B2C), recruitment, small, medium and large team management, team building, entrepreneurship, training, dlgital and traditional marketing, operations improvement, crisis management, franchising. Other skills: Brazilian Portuguese (intermediate), full UK driving license and own car, sense of humour.

Experience

Glenhawk, Mayfair - Full stack developer

February 2020 - Present (2 months)

- Developing a new application to manage a bridging loans company, with the aim to white label and resell.
- Stack includes Laravel 6, Vue.js, Vuetify, MySQL and AWS + Bitbucket repo/CICD.
- Let go due to COVID-19 downsizing in a team of 3, I was the last to join, so first out.

True Compliance, Shoreditch - Full stack developer

February 2019 - February 2020 (12 months)

- Data extract and process from compliance certificates for housing associations.
- First hire alongside founders, scaling a very successful product up and out using Laravel, Vue and AWS.
- Front and back end as well as database migrations and deployments etc. using a microservice architecture.

Twisted Fish, Richmond upon Thames - Full stack developer

January 2018 - February 2019 (13 months)

- Solo responsibility for the development of a business critical ticket helpdesk (PHP + knockout.js) used by 5 companies.
- To solve problems with unacceptable downtime and deployment complexity I introduced docker(engine and swarm) for development and production, jenkins for blue/green deployments, npm and automated testing using codeception.

Suresite Group Ltd, Preston - Junior developer

April 2017 - December 2017 (9 months)

• My first professional IT position (3 person development team in a 50 person office), mainly developing a central customer management system using Laravel, though also working with HTML, MySQL, Linux, Apache etc.

Oxford Direct English, Florianopolis, Brazil - Corporate language trainer June 2015 - March 2017 (1 year 9 months)

- Solopreneur English language training for companies. I trained around 50 staff in 2 Brazilian IT companies.
- This experience improved my B2B sales skills and I also made good friends with many developers and sys admins.

A2Z School of English, Manchester – Founder and director

June 2006 - March 2015 (9 years)

- I founded an English language school in Manchester without funding and grew the company to a turnover of over £1.5 million. We employed > 60 staff and operated in 5 countries, but failed after civil wars in crucial markets (Yemen, Libya).
- The business, sales and cross cultural mindset I acquired can be very helpful in a modern development team.

Other jobs I have done: stock checker, bar man, cafe assistant, binman, youth worker, UK Home Office, waiter, telesales etc.

Education

Oxford University (Exeter College) - BA Hons Theology, 2:1

October 1999 - June 2002

Prior to Oxford I studied at Clitheroe Royal Grammar School, where I obtained three A-levels in Biology, Music and RE.

Outside of work: My wife and 4 kids, science fiction, cryptic crosswords, food and wine, gym.